http://www.thordonbearings.com/legal-notice

Thordon Bearings Inc. ("Thordon") makes this website ("the Site") available to the public - including customers, suppliers, distributors, employees and others. This site is provided for information purposes only. By accessing, using or downloading text, graphics or other information or material from the Site you are agreeing to abide by each of the terms and conditions ("Terms") set out below.
Privacy
At Thordon, the privacy of your personal information has always been an important aspect of how we operate.  On January 1, 2004, the federal Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA) began to apply to provincially regulated organizations that collect, use and disclose personal information in the course of commercial activity.  As such, Thordon has developed the following Privacy Policy in order to ensure compliance with PIPEDA, as well as to inform individuals of our continuing commitment to the protection of their personal information. In May 2018, we reviewed this policy to be compliant with General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) in the EU.
What is personal information?
Personal information includes any factual or subjective information, recorded or not, about an identifiable individual.  This includes information in any form such as a personal e-mail address, home addresses and so on.  It does not include information normally found on a business card, such as name, title, company, business address, business name, business e-mail address, business telephone or fax number.
Objective
Thordon collects and stores information on its employees and customers.  The policy and procedures below outline how this information is managed and used in order to protect the privacy of our employees and customers and to respect the Personal Information and electronic Documents Act and the General Data Protection Regulation.  The purpose of the act is to establish rules to govern the collection, use and disclosure of personal information.
Who is responsible for protecting the personal information collected, used and disclosed by Thordon?
The Human Resource Manager of Thomson-Gordon Group, parent company of Thordon Bearings Inc, is the Chief Privacy Officer for the organization.  The Chief Privacy Officer is responsible for ensuring compliance with PIPEDA, the GDPR and with this Privacy Policy.   At times Thordon staff may be delegated to act on behalf of the Chief Privacy Officer or to take responsibility for occasional collection, use and disclosure of personal information.
You have the option to submit information and materials related to your use of the Website to Thordon by e-mail, through the Site, or by other means to provide feedback, ask questions, or for other purposes ("Submitted Information").
We will only use and/or disclose Submitted Information in order to:
understand and meet your needs and requirements;
develop new and enhance existing product and service offerings;
better manage and develop our business and operations; and
meet legal and regulatory requirements.
Limiting Collection
Thordon restricts the collection of personal information only to that information that is necessary for the limited purposes noted above.  We are committed to collecting personal information in a fair, open and lawful manner.
Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention
Thordon does not use personal information for purposes other than those for which it was originally collected, unless it has first obtained the consent of the person from whom such information was received.
Further, Thordon will only disclose your personal information under the following circumstances.
When we are required or authorized by law to do so
When you have consented to the disclosure
When it is necessary to collect debts
If the information is already publicly known
How is Personal Information Maintained?
Thordon does not sell, barter, trade or give away your personal information to third parties.  Thordon stores and maintains personal information conformity with the requirements of the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act and the General Data Protection Regulation.
Safeguards
Thordon takes all reasonable precautions to ensure that your personal information is kept safe from loss, unauthorized access, modification or disclosure.  We also ensure that any of our employees who deal with personal information are properly trained and are aware of the necessary and appropriate measures required to protect personal information.
How can individuals access their personal information held by Thordon?
Individuals have a right to access their own personal information in the possession and control of Thordon.  However, we reserve the right to confirm the identity of the person seeking access to personal information before complying with any requests.
Changes to This Privacy Policy
Since Thordon regularly reviews all of its policies and procedures, we may change our privacy policy from time to time.
Password Protected Information
Portions of the Site require a user id and a password to access and may require you to agree to additional terms and conditions. To apply for a user id and a password, follow the instructions on the password-protected pages or contact Thordon Customer Service or your local Thordon Distributor.
Revisions To The Site And To These Terms Of Use
Thordon may make changes to the content of this Site or to the products described herein, at any time without notice to you. Thordon, however, makes no commitment to update the content of the Site and does not warrant the accuracy of completeness of the information, text, graphics, links or other content contained within the Site.
Thordon may revise these Terms at any time without notice by updating this posting on the Site. Your continued use of this Site after such modifications have been made will constitute your acceptance of such revised terms and conditions.
Disclaimer of Warranties
ALL MATERIALS, INFORMATION, SOFTWARE, PRODUCTS, SERVICES AND OTHER CONTENT CONTAINED IN THIS SITE, OR OBTAINED FROM A LINKED SITE IS PROVIDED TO YOU "AS IS" WITHOUT WARRANTY OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, WHETHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, TITLE, NON-INFRINGEMENT, SECURITY OR ACCURACY. THORDON HAS MADE REASONABLE EFFORTS TO POST CURRENT AND ACCURATE INFORMATION ON THIS SITE; HOWEVER, THORDON ASSUMES NO RESPONSIBILITY FOR ANY ERRORS, OMISSIONS OR INACCURACIES WHATSOEVER IN THE INFORMATION PROVIDED IN THIS SITE. UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES WILL THORDON BE LIABLE FOR ANY LOSS OR DAMAGE CAUSED BY YOUR RELIANCE ON INFORMATION OBTAINED THROUGH THIS SITE. IT IS YOUR RESPONSIBILITY TO EVALUATE THE ACCURACY, COMPLETENESS AND USEFULNESS OF ANY INFORMATION PROVIDED, AND USE OF THIS SITE IS SOLELY AT YOUR OWN RISK. SOME JURISDICTIONS DO NOT ALLOW THE EXCLUSION OF CERTAIN WARRANTIES, SO THE ABOVE LIMITATIONS OR EXCLUSIONS MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU.
Applicable Law
Any action related to these Terms will be governed by the law in the Province of Ontario, Canada without regard to the choice or conflicts of law provisions of any jurisdiction. You agree to submit to the jurisdiction of the courts located in the Province of Ontario for the resolution of all disputes arising from or relating to these Terms and/or your use of the Site.
Copyright
The Site design, text, graphics, and the selection and arrangement of the design, text and graphics, are the property of Thordon Bearings Inc. unless otherwise noted. Copyright © 2005 Thordon Bearings Inc. All rights reserved.
Global Service & Support
(GSS) Team
Thordon's GSS Team operates 24/7 in more than 100 countries. The GSS team can install, commission, service and maintain the full range of Thordon Bearings' environmentally-safe marine, clean power generation and industrial products. Click here for more information.
To contact Global Service & Support Team:
Call +1.905.335.1440 ext. 7 or use the request form
Request form
